## JEAN PAULO DE ALMEIDA SILVA

Nationality: Brazilian

Address: #468 Farroupilha St, Joinville - Brazil

WhatsApp: +55 47 99717-5383

Email: jeandealmeida.dev@gmail.com

### **Personal Summary**

With over 5 years of experience as an Android Developer, I have a deep understanding of the Android platform and its development ecosystem. One of my key strengths is my ability to collaborate effectively with cross-functional teams, and I am a proactive communicator who is always looking for ways to improve the development process and create a positive team environment. Recently, I have been studying Flutter and have gained knowledge in cross-platform mobile app development. I am also fluent in Spanish and have a high level of proficiency in English.

## **Career History**

Senior Mobile Developer @ XP Inc
October, 2021 ~ February, 2024 | Remote - BRAZIL

- → XP Inc is a Brazilian fintech that provides a range of financial services. Currently I work in the area of investment brokerage, where clients are allowed to invest in a wide range of financial instruments such as stocks, bonds, derivatives, and foreign currencies
- → I collaborate with an experienced team comprising product managers, designers, and other developers to guarantee expectations of stakeholders.
- → Over the past year, I have been engaged as a Flutter developer as the company undergoes a migration of its application to a different technology.

**Technologies**: Kotlin, MVVM Architecture, Android Studio, Google Firebase and Crashlytics, AzureFlutter, Scrum, SSE Connection, Unit tests, Flutter development

# Mid Level Android Developer @ Omnichat November, 2015 ~ October, 2016 | Curitiba - BRAZIL

- → Omnichat is a company specializing in chat-related e-commerce that help companies to offer a better experience selling their products by e.g. whatsapp.
- → I took on the responsibility of building an Android app from scratch during the initial stages of their startup. As a result, I had the autonomy to make decisions regarding the selection of APIs, frameworks, and define the architecture for the app.

**Technologies:** Java, Android Studio, Firebase distribution, MVP Architecture, SQLite, Websocket connection, Firestore

Mid Level Android Developer @ Snowman Labs June, 2015 ~ October, 2015 | Curitiba - BRAZIL

- → It is a software house based in Brazil. They provide end-to-end services, including app design, development, testing, and maintaining apps. They create user-friendly applications that meet their customers' specifications.
- → During that time, I was involved in various stages of the project, starting from analyzing customer requirements and proceeding to prototyping and system development.

**Technologies:** Java, Android Studio, MVP Architecture, SQLite, Restfull connection, Firestore and Firebase

Junior to Mid Level Android Developer @ Totvs February, 2014 ~ May, 2015 | Joinville - BRAZIL

- → It is a Brazilian multinational software company that specializes in the development and implementation of ERP (enterprise resource planning) software solutions. They are one of the largest software companies in Latin America
- → At Totvs, We were a small mobile team responsible for managing their business process management app. Our first goal as a team was to release the new app and fix bugs of legacy code.

**Technologies:** Java, Android Studio, MVP Architecture, SQLite, Restfull connection, Firestore and Firebase, Kanban methodology, Pair programming

# Intern to Junior Developer @ Softin Sistemas May, 2012 ~ January, 2014 | Joinville - BRAZIL

- → It is a Brazilian company that specializes in providing solutions for technical assistance and service network management.
- → In the initial phase, as trainee, my role was to develop and improve their web tool with .NET C# focusing on TDD for managing and optimizing technical support and service networks.
- → Later, I was assigned to develop a new Android app for technicians. This app helps them to manage the progress, execution, and location of their services.

**Technologies**: Java, C#, .NET, Silverlight, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Scrum, Pair Programming, TDD

#### Education

Bachelor of Computer Science

Santa Catarina State University | Joinville - BRAZIL

2010 ~ 2014

### Skills

- → Resilience
- → Teamwork and respectful attitude
- → Methodical, accurate and patient.
- → Positive and energetic personality
- → Ability to work under pressure.
- → Spirit of Commitment to Work
- → Skilled at problem solving and decision making
- → Driver License And Passport
- → Continuous Learning and self improvement

# **Technical Experienced Skills**

- → Experienced Android user
- → Fundamentals of Mobile UI/UX
- → Java and Kotlin Programming Languages
- → Python Programming Language
- → TDD and Unit tests
- → Jetpack Compose and Custom Views
- → Reactive Programming

- → Dependency Injection
- → Source Code Management (Git/Svn)
- → Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD) using GitHub Actions
- → Google Firebase Remote Config, Crashlytics, Firestore
- → MVP, MVVM, Clean Architecture

#### Personal Achievements

- → In 2015, I undertook a 1-month exchange program in the city of Montreal, Canada, with the main goal of improving my English and learning a new language, French.
- → In 2017, I took a break to travel through South America. It helped me grow as a person as I learned to be independent, resilient, and adaptable. This journey expanded my worldview and inspired me to welcome new challenges.
- → In 2023, I spent three months in New Zealand, exploring the country and immersing myself in the English language on a daily basis.

# Languages

→ Portuguese: Native Language

→ Spanish: Fluent→ English: Advanced